<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="checklist3x3Tab">Checklist</string>
    <string name="checklist_3x3_heading">3x3 Filter Method</string>
    <string name="checklist_3x3_desc">The 3x3 Filter Method is a method developed by Werner Munter for assessing
        aspects contributing to the risk of an avalanche.  It provides three levels of checks for each of the 
        three decision making stages before and while on the mountain.  This application provides a reminder checklist 
        to help you consider important aspects for your decision making.\n\n
        It is important to fully understand each point in this checklist through appropriate training
        and reading.  It is not this checklist that provides the safety, but the understanding of the factors
        behind the checklist.\n\n
        It is a good idea to work on memorising this checklist during the season, especially the zonal aspects.  It is
        not always practical to pull out your phone and work through this checklist while making decisions
        on the mountain.  This is especially the case in extreme conditions where you may need to make fast decisions
        adapting to changing conditions.    </string>
    <string name="conditions">Snow and Weather Conditions</string>
    <string name="terrain">Terrain</string>
    <string name="human">Human Factor</string>
    <string name="regional">Regional\nPre-departure preparation, including alternatives</string>
    <string name="regional_cond_a">Avalanche bulletin, national, local and automatic</string>
    <string name="regional_cond_b">Weather forecast</string>
    <string name="regional_cond_c">Expert opinions and information</string>
    <string name="regional_terrain_a">A large scale map, preferably 1:25,000</string>
    <string name="regional_terrain_b">Guide books, photos, air photos</string>
    <string name="regional_terrain_c">Personal and local knowledge of the area</string>
    <string name="regional_human_a">Who is planning to come? Level of experience, skill, physical fitness, mental strength</string>
    <string name="regional_human_b">Check equipment: Transceiver, shovel, probe (harness?)</string>
    <string name="regional_human_c">Is there a designated leader?</string>
    <string name="local">Local\nWithin range of vision.  Selection of route and alternatives</string>
    <string name="local_cond_a">Wind loading; Ripples, dunes or sastrugi from Wind</string>
    <string name="local_cond_b">Signs of danger; Snow condition; Recent avalanche activity</string>
    <string name="local_cond_c">Amount of new snow</string>
    <string name="local_cond_d">Are conditions inverted? Northern slopes safer than South? Higher safer than lower?</string>
    <string name="local_cond_e">Föhn/Chinook winds or rain can quickly reduce the stability of the snow pack</string>
    <string name="local_cond_f">Visibility, Clouds, Wind speed</string>
    <string name="local_cond_g">Temperature changes</string>
    <string name="local_cond_h">Is the bulletin correct?  Make changes in case of doubt</string>
    <string name="local_terrain_a">Slope steepness (including above and below), aspect(s), size</string>
    <string name="local_terrain_b">Are the tracks left by previous riders suitable for current conditions?</string>
    <string name="local_human_a">Who is in the group?  How many?</string>
    <string name="local_human_b">Transceiver check. Check other equipment: shovels, probes (harnesses?)</string>
    <string name="local_human_c">Are other groups traveling on the same route?  Do the different groups need coordinating?</string>
    <string name="local_human_d">On time or is it getting too late?</string>
    <string name="zonal">Zonal\nCheck the slope in front of you</string>
    <string name="zonal_cond_a">How much new snow has fallen on the slope?</string>
    <string name="zonal_cond_b">Recent snow drift accumulations?</string>
    <string name="zonal_cond_c">Visibility.  Is bad weather closing in?</string>
    <string name="zonal_cond_d">Influence of solar radiation?</string>
    <string name="zonal_cond_e">Where could a slab release and how big could it be?</string>
    <string name="zonal_cond_f">Look at everything around; What is the overall picture?</string>
    <string name="zonal_terrain_a">What is above and below me? Other people?</string>
    <string name="zonal_terrain_b">How steep is the steepest section? In Couloirs this is usually the sides, not the middle.</string>
    <string name="zonal_terrain_c">Aspect? In Couloirs there can be multiple aspects.</string>
    <string name="zonal_terrain_d">Typical avalanche terrain: Steep, rocky slope; Steep leeward slope; Steep shaded forest glade</string>
    <string name="zonal_terrain_e">Slope shape; concave, convex, S-shape</string>
    <string name="zonal_terrain_f">Elevation</string>
    <string name="zonal_human_a">Ability, discipline, fatigue of group members</string>
    <string name="zonal_human_b">Is the slope frequently tracked?</string>
    <string name="zonal_human_c">Safety distance; One at a time; Follow the same path</string>
    <string name="zonal_human_d">Identify "Islands of safety" as meeting points</string>
    <string name="zonal_human_e">Avoid dangerous areas and risky routes</string>
    <string name="lastCheck">Last check\nTo go or not to go.  Does everybody in the group agree with a go decision?</string>

</resources>