<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="infoTab">Info</string>
    <string name="hazard_heading">Hazard levels</string>
    <string name="hazard_desc">
        The hazard level used in the avalanche bulletin is an internationally recognised standard for identifying the general
        risk level of avalanches in the mountains. This is a combination of snow pack stability and the probability of 
        triggering an avalanche. This is then broken up into five hazard levels.
        \n\nThese hazard levels only give a general guide of the chances of triggering an avalanche and should always
        be used in conjunction with experience and the detailed information provided in the avalanche bulletin.
    </string>
    <string name="hazard_level_1_desc">
        The snowpack as a whole is secure. Naturally triggered avalanches are unlikely other than smaller slides on steep slopes. 
        Even on extremely steep slopes, high levels of additional stress are required to trigger an avalanche.
        \n\nOff piste and back country conditions are generally regarded as being safe, with danger zones being rare and 
        easily identified.
    </string>
    <string name="hazard_level_2_desc">
        The snowpack on some steep slopes is only moderately bonded, as described in the avalanche bulletin.
        Naturally triggered avalanches are unlikely and, for carefully chosen routes, conditions are predominantley favourable.
        Nevertheless, there is still a possibility of triggering an avalanche, especially under higher loads such as a group
        riding or ascending close together. Steep slopes with unfavourable snow conditions have the possibility of being
        triggered by an individual rider.
        \n\nHighly trafficed routes and controlled off piste conditions are generally safe.
    </string>
    <string name="hazard_level_3_desc">
        The snowpack is moderately or poorly bonded on most steep slopes, especially those described in the avalanche bulletin.
        Medium sized naturally triggered avalanches are possible and on rare occassions may be large.
        Off piste and back country routes require extensive experience and caution.
        \n\nEven a single rider can trigger an avalanche in these conditions, especially on steep slopes.
    </string>
    <string name="hazard_level_4_desc">
        The snowpack is poorly bonded on most steep slopes.
        Natural and human triggered avalanches are likely, and can be large.
        \n\nTravel in avalanche terrain is not recommended. 
    </string>
    <string name="hazard_level_5_desc">
        The snowpack is extremely unstable and can form large slabs.
        Natural and human triggered avalanches are certain, and are likely to be large.
        \n\nEven travel in flat terrain is risky if avalanche runout areas are not carefully avoided.
    </string>
    <string name="reduction_heading">Reduction Method</string>
    <string name="reduction_desc">
        It is never possible to be 100% sure that it is safe to ride a certain slope without triggering an avalanche.
        The reduction method is a formula that was developed by Werner Munter to help reduce the risk of triggering an avalanche
        to an acceptable level. It combines the danger level in the avalanche bulletin with a number of safety measures, 
        or reduction factors, to produce an estimate of the risk of an avalanche.
        \n\nThis formula assigns a number to the avalanche risk level in the avalanche bulletin, called the danger potential.
        It then assigns numbers to various reduction factors that you can use to reduce the risk.
        For the risk level to be acceptable, multiplying all the reduction factors together must produce a number greater than 
        the danger potential.
        \n\nThis is intended as a planning tool to help determine if your planned route is appropriate for the current avalanche
        conditions. It only produces an estimate for the general conditions of the trip and should be used in conjunction 
        with the 3x3 Filter Method, training and knowledge of avalanche risk.
        \n\nThe reduction method is designed to be used in northern latitudes between 35° and 55°, which covers most popular ski 
        areas.  Extra caution must be used in far northern areas such as Alaska and Scandinavia as weaker solar radiation makes 
        the snow pack less stable.  It must also be adapted for the southern hemisphere.
        \n\nThis description is only a brief overview of the reduction method and is not a substitute for reading expert literature
        and attending training provided by avalanche professionals.
	</string>
	<string name="threex3_heading">3x3 Filter Method</string>
    <string name="threex3_desc">The 3x3 Filter Method is a method developed by Werner Munter to help with assessing
        aspects contributing to the risk of an avalanche. It provides three stages of checks, with three types of factors,
        to be used in the decision making process before and while on the mountain. This application provides a 
        reminder checklist to remind you to consider important factors for making decisions before and while travelling in
        avalanche terrain.
        \n\nThis checklist is just that, merely a checklist. It is important to fully understand each point in this checklist through 
        appropriate training and reading. It is not ticking off items on this checklist that provides the safety, but having
        a thorough understanding of the factors behind each and every item on the checklist.
        \n\nIt is a good idea to work on memorising this checklist during the season, especially the zonal aspects. It won\'t
        always be practical to pull out your phone and work through this checklist while making decisions
        on the mountain. This is especially the case in extreme conditions where you may need to make fast decisions
        adapting to changing conditions, or when you and your mates are excited about hitting up fresh tracks.
        It should be your ambition to know and understand these factors deeply and instinctively enough that this phone 
        application becomes unecessary.
        \n\nThis description is only a brief overview of the 3x3 Filter Method and is not a substitute for reading expert literature
        and attending training provided by avalanche professionals.
	</string>

	<string name="books_heading">Book References</string>
    <string name="threex3LawinenBook_title">3x3 Lawinen (German)</string>
	<string name="threex3LawinenBook">\tWerner Munter\n\t&#169; 2009 Verlag Pohl &amp; Schellhammer\n\tISBN 3-00-010520-4</string>
    <string name="PowderGuideBook_title">Powder Guide (English)</string>
    <string name="PowderGuideBook">\tTobias Kurzeder and Holger Feist\n\t&#169; 2003 Mountain Sports Press\n\tISBN 0-9724827-3-3</string>
    
	<string name="links_heading">Links</string>

</resources>